A Guide to the Minutes of the Virginia Fire Services Board, 1978-2013.
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Minutes of the Virginia Fire Services Board,
1978-2013.
The Library of Virginia
50267, 50889, 52057
Virginia Fire Services Board.
6.7 cu. ft.
Administrative Information
Arranged chronologically.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions
Acquisition Information
Accession 50267 transferred by the Virginia Dept. of Fire Programs, 12 Dec 2011.
Accession 50889 transferred by the Virginia Dept. of Fire Programs, 29 Mar 2013.
Accession 52057 transferred by the Virginia Dept. of Fire Programs, 8 Oct 2017.
Historical Information
The Virginia State Fire Services Commission and the Office of Fire Service Training was created by an act of the General Assembly in 1978. This act was amended in 1981 to replace Virginia State Fire Services Commission and the Office of Fire Service Training with the Department of Fire Programs. The agency was established to receive and disburse funds available to the Commonwealth under the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act. The act also established the Virginia Fire Services Board within the Department of Fire Programs to consist of fifteen members appointed by the governor for a term of four years. The department's mission is to provide funding, training, and educational programs to enhance public safety throughout the Commonwealth.
Scope and Content
Minutes, 1978-2013, document the meetings, activities, discussions, policy decisions and recommendations of the Virginia Fire Services Board. Includes agendas and original signed minutes, as well as draft minutes, committee minutes and subcommittee minutes. Also may include meeting packet information and attachments including budgets, bylaws, correspondence, legislation, memoranda, notices, plans, policies, procedures, public hearing comments, publications, reading material, reports, regulations, resolutions, and training and conference materials. The minutes often provide reports of the Executive Director and reports from the various standing committees. Committees may include Code Change and Development Committee, Executive/Finance/Administration Policy Committee, Fire and EMS Training and Education Committee, Fire Prevention and Control Committee, Legislative/Liaison Committee, and the Residential Sprinkler Committee. Also includes meeting information for the Ad Hoc Committee Studying Concurrent Jurisdiction (1993), Aid to Localities Ad Hoc Committee (2012), Burn Building Subcommittee and the Codes and Standards Subcommittee.
Includes minutes in paper (1978-1984, 1987-1992, 1993-1999, 2000-2007, 2009-2013) and in electronic format (2008, 860.2 mb). Minutes often consist of Board Books/Packets distributed at meetings that include agendas, draft minutes for the full board and committee meetings for the previous meeting.
Contents List
- Minutes of the Virginia Fire Services Board, 1978-2013.
  - Accession 50267 (1993-1994, 1999-2007, 2009)., Extent: 3 cu. ft. (3 boxes); 5.04 mb
    Includes minutes and draft minutes, 1993-1994, 1999-2007, 2009, for the full board as well as for committees. Also includes board meeting packet information and attachments.
    Minutes of the Virginia Fire Services Board, 2008, are also available in electronic format (.doc, .pdf) (5.04 mb, 7 folders, 56 files). Includes Board minutes and agendas, and Committee minutes and agendas (Fire Education and Training Committee, Fire Prevention and Control Committee, and Administration, Policy and Finance Committee). Also include 5 Year Master Plan for Training, 2009. For file inventory for this accession, see: Inventory (50267).
    - Minutes, 1993 Feb. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Minutes, 1993 Apr. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Minutes, 1993 June. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Minutes, 1993 Aug. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Minutes, 1993 Oct. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Minutes, 1993 Dec. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Minutes, 1994 Feb. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Minutes, 1994 Apr. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Minutes, 1994 June. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Minutes, 1994 Aug. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Minutes, 1994 Oct. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Minutes, 1999 Arp 8-9. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Minutes, 1999 June 10-11. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Minutes, 1999 Aug 11-13. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Minutes, 1999 Oct 14-15. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Minutes, 1999 Dec 2-3. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Minutes, 2000 Feb 17-18. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Minutes, 2000 Apr 13-14. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Minutes, 2000 June 15-16. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Minutes (Part I), 2001 Apr 19-20. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Minutes (Part II), 2001 Apr 19-20. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Minutes, 2001 June 14-15. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Minutes, 2001 Aug 19-20. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Minutes, 2001 Oct 11-12. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Minutes, 2001 Dec 6-7. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Minutes, 2002 Feb 21-22. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Minutes, 2002 Apr 4-5. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Minutes, 2002 June 7-8. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Minutes, 2002 Aug 16-17. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Minutes, 2002 Oct 3-4. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Minutes, 2002 Dec 5-6. (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Minutes, 2003 Feb 20-21. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Minutes, 2003 Aug 15-16. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Minutes, 2003 Dec 4-5. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Minutes, 2004 Feb 26-27. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Minutes, 2004 Apr 19-20. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Minutes, 2004 June 4-5. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Minutes, 2004 Aug 20-21. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Minutes, 2004 Oct 14-15. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Minutes, 2004 Dec 2-3. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Minutes, 2005 Feb 24-25. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Minutes, 2005 Apr 21-22. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Minutes, 2005 June 3-4. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Minutes, 2005 Aug 19-20. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Minutes, 2005 Oct 13-14. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Minutes (Part I), 2005 Dec 1-2. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Minutes (Part II), 2005 Dec 1-2. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Minutes, 2006 Feb 24-25. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Minutes, 2006 Apr 20-21. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Minutes, 2006 June 2-3. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Minutes, 2006 Aug 11-12. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Minutes, 2006 Oct 12-13. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Minutes, 2006 Dec 13-14. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Minutes, 2007 Feb 21-24. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Minutes (Part I), 2007 Apr 11-13. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Minutes (Part II), 2007 Apr 11-13. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Minutes, 2007 May 31-June 2. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Minutes (cd), 2008. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Minutes, 2009 Jan. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Minutes, 2009 Feb. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Minutes, 2009 Mar. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Minutes, 2009 Apr. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Minutes, 2009 June. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Minutes, 2009 Aug. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Minutes, 2009 Oct. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Minutes, 2009 Dec. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Five Year Master Plan for Training, 2009. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Accession 52057 (1978-1984, 1987-1992, 1995-1998 and 2013)., Extent: 3 cu. ft. (3 boxes)
    Includes original, signed minutes and draft minutes, 1978-1984, 1987-1992, 1995-1998 and 2013, for the full board as well as for committees. Later years also include board meeting packet information and attachments.
    - Minutes, 1978 Oct, Nov, Dec. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Minutes, 1979. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Minutes, 1980. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Minutes, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Minutes, 1982. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Minutes, 1983 Jan, Mar, May. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Minutes, 1983 July, Oct. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Minutes, 1984 Jan, Mar, May. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Minutes, 1984 July, Oct, Nov. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Minutes, 1987 Feb, Apr. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Minutes, 1987 June. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Minutes, 1987 Aug. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Minutes, 1987 Oct, Dec. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Minutes, 1988 Jan, Mar. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Minutes, 1988 Apr, June. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Minutes, 1988 Aug, Oct, Dec. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Minutes, 1989 Feb, Mar. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Minutes, 1989 Apr. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Minutes, 1989 June, Aug. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Minutes, 1989 Oct, Dec. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Minutes, 1990 Feb, Apr. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Minutes, 1990 June, Aug. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Minutes, 1990 Oct, Dec. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Minutes, 1991 Feb, Apr. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Minutes, 1991 June. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Minutes, 1991 Oct, Dec. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Minutes, 1992 Feb, Apr. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Minutes, 1992 June. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Minutes, 1992 Aug. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Minutes, 1992 Oct, Dec. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Minutes, 1995 Feb. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Minutes, 1995 Apr. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Minutes, 1995 June. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Minutes, 1995 Aug. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Minutes, 1995 Oct. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Minutes, 1995 Dec. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Minutes, 1996 Jan. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Minutes (Part I), 1996 Feb. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Minutes (Part II), 1996 Feb. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Minutes (Part III), 1996 Feb. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Minutes, 1996 Mar. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Minutes (Part I), 1996 Apr. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Minutes (Part II), 1996 Apr. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Minutes (Part I), 1996 June. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Minutes (Part II), 1996 June. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Minutes, 1996 Aug. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Minutes, 1996 Oct. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Minutes (Part I), 1996 Dec. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Minutes (Part II), 1996 Dec. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Minutes (Draft), 1996 Dec. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Minutes, 1997 Feb. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Minutes, 1997 Apr. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Minutes, 1997 June. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Minutes, 1997 Aug. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Minutes, 1997 Oct. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Minutes, 1997 Dec. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Minutes, 1998 Feb. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Minutes, 1998 Apr. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Minutes, 1998 June, Aug. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Minutes, 1998 Sept, Oct. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Minutes, 1998 Dec. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Indexed table of passed motions and action items by the Virginia Fire Services Board and its committees, 1992-2004. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Minutes - Burn Building Subcommittee, 2013 Jan 24. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Minutes - Full Board, 2013 Feb 22. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Minutes - Burn Building Subcommittee, 2013 Apr 11. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Minutes - Codes and Standards Subcommittee, 2013 May 3. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Minutes - Codes and Standards Subcommittee, 2013 May 30. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Minutes - Full Board, 2013 May 31. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Minutes - Burn Building Subcommittee, 2013 July 11. (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Minutes - Full Board, 2013 Aug 16. (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Minutes - Full Board, 2013 Nov 15. (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Minutes - Training and Education Committee, 2013 Dec 9. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Accession 50889 (2010-2012)., Extent: .7 cu. ft. (2 boxes)
    Includes Board meeting packets with draft minutes and attachments. Also includes meeting packets for the Aid to Localities Ad Hoc Committee, Burn Building Subcommittee and Codes and Standards Subcommittee.
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Full Board, 2010 Feb 25-26. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Full Board, 2010 Apr 8-9. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Full Board, 2010 June 4-5. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Full Board, 2010 Aug 13-14. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Full Board, 2010 Oct 7-8. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Full Board, 2010 Dec 2-3. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Full Board, 2011 Feb 24-25. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Full Board, 2011 Apr 7-8. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Full Board, 2011 June 3-4. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Full Board, 2011 Aug 12-13. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Full Board, 2011 Oct 6-7. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Full Board, 2011 Dec 1-2. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Burn Building Subcommittee, 2011 Jan 20. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Burn Building Subcommittee, 2011 Mar 3. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Burn Building Subcommittee, 2011 May 5. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Burn Building Subcommittee, 2011 July 7. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Codes and Standards Subcommittee, 2011 Sept 28. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Full Board, 2012 Feb 23-24. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Full Board, 2012 June 1-2. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Full Board, 2012 Aug 17-18. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Full Board, 2012 Nov 30. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Burn Building Subcommittee, 2012 Jan 26. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Burn Building Subcommittee, 2012 July 12. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Burn Building Subcommittee, 2012 Sept 13. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Codes and Standards Subcommittee, 2012 Jan 18. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Codes and Standards Subcommittee, 2012 July 18. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Codes and Standards Subcommittee, 2012 Oct 17. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Codes and Standards Subcommittee, 2012 Dec 5. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Minutes / Meeting packets - Aid to Localities (ATL) Ad Hoc Committee, 2012 Jan 31. (Box 2, Folder 19)